{
  "sourceFile": "2019-2020-International-Geography-Bee-Regional-Quiz-Tournament-Round-2.txt",
  "count": 10,
  "items": [
    {
      "qno": 1,
      "question": "This country’s southernmost portion is St. Martin’s Island, which lies at the mouth of the Naf River. This country’s current construction boom is fueled by the stone industry in the town of Jaflong. This country’s principle port is located at Chittagong, which is located near this country’s border with Myanmar. For ten points, name this low lying south Asian country with capital Dhaka.",
      "answer": "Bangladesh"
    },
    {
      "qno": 2,
      "question": "These structures can be confirmed by the presence of breccia and shatter cones. The largest verified example of these structures is found near Vredefort, South Africa. Mt. Mazama in Oregon holds a lake named for being in one of these structures. Volcanic eruptions sometimes form, for ten points, what structures whose impact variety is created when meteors or asteroids collide with the Earth?",
      "answer": "craters"
    },
    {
      "qno": 3,
      "question": "In this country, theme parks like Dreamworld and Wet’n’Wild are located in the city of Gold Coast. Another beach town in this country is Byron Bay, which is known for its humpback whales. This country’s other coastal towns include Darwin, Perth, and Adelaide. The Bass Strait in this country contains its city of Melbourne. For ten points, name this land “Down Under” with capital Canberra.",
      "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
      "qno": 4,
      "question": "The largest example of these structures is Borobudur, located in Java, Indonesia. Reliquaries in these structures are known as stupas. In East Asia, these structures are often accompanied by tiered towers called Pagodas. Although originally founded as a Hindu Temple, Angkor Wat now serves as one of these structures. For ten points, name these buildings, where practitioners of a religion founded by Siddartha Guatama worship.",
      "answer": "Buddhist temples"
    },
    {
      "qno": 5,
      "question": "This island’s Kalimantan states are home to the Dayak people, who were oppressed by the Brooke Raja regime on this island. This island’s north contains the state of Sabah, while the state of Sarawak on this island is home to an orangutan reservation. The Sultanate of Brunei is located on, for ten points, what island split between Malaysia and Indonesia, the third largest in the world?",
      "answer": "Borneo"
    },
    {
      "qno": 6,
      "question": "The Lorelai Rock sits on the shores of this river, where a beautiful maiden was said to lure sailors into crashing their ships. The Neckar and Main rivers flow into this other river, which flows past the city of Cologne. This river forms the borders between Liechtenstein, Austria, and Switzerland. For ten points, name this European river that flows through Germany on its way to the North Sea.",
      "answer": "The Rhine Page 1 IGB Regionals 2019-2020 Round 2"
    },
    {
      "qno": 7,
      "question": "This mountain’s north and south summits were renamed in honor of Winston Churchill in 1965. The Kahiltna Glacier originated from this mountain. William Dickey is credited with discovering this mountain, whose name translated from Athabaskan as “the High One.” For ten points, identify this Alaskan mountain, formerly named for an American President, the tallest in North America.",
      "answer": "Denali"
    },
    {
      "qno": 8,
      "question": "This archipelago’s largest volcano is located on Fernandina Island. The largest island in this archipelago is Isabella. This archipelago is the only native habitat of the flightless cormorant and the marine iguana. The Voyage of the Beagle was written about a trip to this archipelago. For ten points, name this archipelago off the coast of Ecuador, where Charles Darwin studied its tortoises and finches.",
      "answer": "Galapagos Islands"
    },
    {
      "qno": 9,
      "question": "This country is home to a vegetarian dish eaten by monks called Buddha’s delight. Another dish from this country is prepared by aging an egg in a mixture of clay, ash, salt, and quicklime. In addition to century eggs, this country is home to a pastry filled with red bean paste that is eaten during the Mid-Autumn festival. Mooncakes are from, for ten points, what country whose other dishes include chow mein?",
      "answer": "China"
    },
    {
      "qno": 10,
      "question": "This desert is home to the Dohone Spur, which contains the mountain Bikku Bitti. The shield volcano Emi Koussi is the highest peak found in this desert. Both of those mountains are found in this desert’s Tibesti Mountains. This desert is home to the Tuareg people. This desert extends from the Sahel to the Mediterranean Sea. For ten points, name this largest desert in the world, located in northern Africa.",
      "answer": "Sahara Desert"
    }
  ]
}